Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the United Federation of Teachers PE.015
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the United Federation of Teachers
1942-2008
1950-1980
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
Hamerman, Josh
PE.015
4 Linear Feet in 3 record cartons and 3 shared boxes
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the United Federation of Teachers (1942-2008, bulk 1950-1980) contains materials created by United Federation of Teachers (UFT) which represents public school teachers and associated personnel in New York City. This collection contains a variety of printed ephemera including constitutions, agreements, brochures, clippings, flyers, pamphlets, reports and other items reflecting the history and activities of the union. The United Federation of Teachers is associated with the American Federation of Teachers as Local 2.
Arrangement
Files without titles are arranged chronologically, followed by titled files arranged alphabetically. All Agreements are at the end of the file list.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Scope and Content Note
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the United Federation of Teachers (1942-2008, bulk 1950-1980) consists of files of printed ephemera such as constitutions, agreements, brochures, clippings, flyers, pamphlets, reports, and other documents relating to activities and history of New York City's United Federation of Teachers, which is Local 2, of the American Federation of Teachers.
Historical Note
The United Federation of Teachers represents most of the public school teachers and associated personnel in New York City. It was formed in 1960 as a result of a merger between the Teachers Guild and the High School Teachers Association and, in December of 1961, became the collective bargaining organization for all New York City teachers. It is affiliated with the American Federation of Teachers, the AFL-CIO and the Central Labor Council. It is also the largest member of New York State United Teachers, which is affililated with the National Educational Association and Education International.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
United Federation of Teachers Records (WAG 022)
United Federation of Teachers: Italian-American Studies Committee Records (WAG 056)
United Federation of Teachers Oral History Collection (OH 009)
United Federation of Teachers Photographs (PHOTOS 019)
United Federation of Teachers Photographs Hans Weissenstein Negatives Collection (PHOTOS 019 001)
Custodial History
The Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives accumulated this artificial collection of printed ephemera gradually over the years through purchases, donations, standing orders with publishers, organizations, and bookstores, and through exchanges with other special library collections and by ongoing collecting by staff.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials in this collection have been compiled by the Tamiment Library.
Josh Hamerman donated a United Federation of Teachers Handbook in 2014. The accession number associated with this gift is 2014.017.
In 2025, materials from accession 2019.056, which is associated with Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on Subjects (PE 029), were transferred to this collection.
Clippings (information artifacts); Pamphlets.; Constitutions.; Memorandums.; Agreements.; Collective labor agreements.; Kolodny, Jules; Hamerman, Josh; United Federation of Teachers
- 1942, 1949 (Box 1)
- 1950-1958 (Box 1)
- 1959 (Box 1)
- 1960 (Box 1)
- 1961 (Box 1)
- 1962 (Box 1)
- 1963 I (Box 1)
- 1963 II (Box 1)
- 1964 (Box 1)
- 1965-1966 (Box 1)
- 1967 (Box 1)
- 1968 (Box 1)
- 1969 (Box 1)
- 1970 (Box 1)
- 1971-1972 (Box 1)
- 1973-1979 (Box 1)
- 1980-1985 (Box 1)
- 1987-1990 (Box 1)
- 1995-2000 (Box 1)
- undated (Box 1)
- Benefits, 1986-1989 (Box 1)
- Chalk Dust, 1982-1986 (Box 1)
- Chapter Chairman's Handbook, 1965 (Box 1)
- Chapter Chairman's Handbook, 1976 (Box 1)
- Chronology/History, 1960, 1985 (Box 1)
- Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW), circa 1980 (Box 1)
- Coalition of New York City School Workers, 1980, undated (Box 1)
- Cogan, Charles, 1998 (Box 1)
- Collective Bargaining Program, 1972 (Box 1)
- Constitutions, 1970-1998 (Box 1)
- Department of Communications: Newsclips, Jan 1981 (Box 1)
- Election, 1962, undated (Box 2)
- Election, 1964 (Box 2)
- Ephemera, 1973 (Box 2)
- Jaffe, Sol, circa 1965 (Box Shared Tamiment 190, Folder 18)
- Kolodny, Jules, 1985 (Box 2)
- Labor History, undated (Box 2)
- New Action Coalition, 1983-1985, undated (Box 2)
- New Coalition Caucus, 1968 (Box 2)
- Newspaper Clippings and Articles, 1965-2001 (Box 2)
- Pamphlets and Publications I, 1964-2005, undated (Box 2)
- Pamphlets and Publications II, 1964-2005, undated (Box 2)
- Placards, undated (Box Shared Tamiment MSXOS001)
- Pension Handbook, 1973 (Box 2)
- Rank and File, 1967, undated (Box 2)
- Shanker, Albert, 1969 (Box Shared Tamiment 190, Folder 19, Box Shared Tamiment 184, Folder 30)
- Spring Conference Programs, 1958-2001 (Box 2)
- Story of UFT (Publication), 1966 (Oversize 2)
- Strike of 1968: Paper on, 2008 (Box 2)
- Teachers Action Caucus, 1967-1971 (Box 2)
- Teachers Action Caucus, 1972-1973 (Box 2)
- Teachers Action Caucus, 1974 (Box 2)
- Teachers Action Caucus, 1975-1979 (Box 2)
- Teachers Action Caucus, 1980-1987, 1990 (Box 2)
- Teachers Action Caucus, undated (Box 2)
- Teachers for a Democratic Society, undated (Box 2)
- United Teacher, 1960-1965 (Oversize 2)
- Welfare Fund, 1971, 1974 (Box 2)
- Welfare Fund: Annual Reports, 1966-1976 (Box 2)
- Wittes, David M., 1972 (Box 2)
- Agreements, 1965 (Box 2)
- Agreements, 1967 (Box 2)
- Agreements, 1968 (Box 2)
- Agreements, 1969 (Box 2)
- Agreements, 1972 (Box 2)
- Agreements, 1975 (Box 2)
- Agreements, 1975 (Box 3)
- Agreements, 1977 (Box 3)
- Agreements I, 1982 (Box 3)
- Agreements II, 1982 (Box 3)
- Agreements, 1984 (Box 3)
- Agreements, 1987 (Box 3)
- Agreements, 1989 (Box 3)
- Agreements, 1990 (Box 3)
- Agreements: Registered Nurses, 1980 (Box 3)
- Oversize Folder (see VF Oversize Drawers) Contents: United Teacher (Box ?)